ups.com 2000-03-03

# UPS Privacy Policy

|   
---  

| UPS at a Glance  
| The UPS Story  
| Year 2000 Readiness Disclosure  
| UPS Privacy Policy  
|   
  |   
|   |  Protection of Customer Information  
---|---  
  |  Shipment Information  
  |  Links To Other Sites  
  |  Security And Integrity Of Information  
  |  Retention Of Customer Information  
  |  Customers Are Responsible For Protecting Information And Systems On Their Premises  
  |  The UPS Web Site At WWW.UPS.COM  
  |  Assent  
  |  Contacting UPS  
|   
  
**PROTECTION OF CUSTOMER INFORMATION**  
  
We understand the importance of privacy to our customers and visitors to our Web site. For many years, our policy has been to treat what we learn about our customers as confidential. For example, we will not give or sell confidential or personal information about our customer to any third party not affiliated with their transaction, except as required by law or as necessary to provide UPS services to the customer. 

We collect and store information about every package we handle so that we can efficiently provide the package delivery services demanded by our customers. We use information about our customers, their packages, and their shipping activity to provide or enhance the services we make available to our customers, to enhance our ability to communicate with our customers about additional services they may find of value, to satisfy our legitimate business interests (including performing trend analysis and market studies), to set prices, establish credit, fulfill a Contract of Carriage or Service Agreement, accomplish the billing function, and to comply with government regulations. Although government regulations vary in the many countries in which we operate, they frequently include the reporting of information to transportation safety, customs, and other regulatory agencies. 

As we collect and use information about our customers, we may contract with vendors to assist us in processing that information. These vendors are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are restricted from using the information for any purpose other than helping to provide UPS services to our customers. 

Some of the information collected by UPS is personal data or data which relates to an identifiable person. Examples of personal data are names, addresses, e-mail addresses, credit card numbers and telephone numbers. We never sell information to third parties that could be used to specifically identify an individual customer or group of customers. Anonymized data, with all names, addresses and other personally identifiable information removed, is sometimes shared with third parties. Finally, we do provide personal data to government agencies as required by law or regulation. 

In addition to the uses of the information described in the paragraphs above, we collect telephone numbers and e-mail addresses in the event that we have to contact the shipper, or the shipment recipient, to resolve a question or provide shipment status information. 

Top of Page

**SHIPMENT INFORMATION**  
  
Information, including personal information (name, address and phone number), provided as part of a shipping transaction represents a record of that business transaction and cannot be altered after the transaction is complete except as provided in the UPS Terms and Conditions. The UPS Terms and Conditions are available at [www.ups.com](http://www.ups.com/) in the Service Guide section and at local UPS offices. 

Although we make reasonable efforts to limit access to our facilities and vehicles to authorized personnel, we are not responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of information that is printed and placed in plain view on a package or letter. 

Top of Page

**LINKS TO OTHER SITES**  
  
UPS provides links to external sites as a convenience to the user. The inclusion of any link does not imply UPS endorsement of the external site company, its web site, or the products and services it promotes and sells. UPS is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

Top of Page

**SECURITY AND INTEGRITY OF INFORMATION**  
  
We treat our data as assets that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ information security techniques to appropriately protect confidential information from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company. Access to customer information is limited to those employees who have a legitimate business need for that information. 

UPS Internet sites are currently located in the United States. UPS Internet sites, and their supporting systems, employ generally accepted information security techniques such as firewalls, access control procedures and cryptography to appropriately protect confidential information from unauthorized access. 

Top of Page

**RETENTION OF CUSTOMER INFORMATION**  
  
We retain information about customers as necessary for business purposes and as required by government regulation. For example, we retain information about packages, including names and addresses, so that we can provide proof of delivery information and to process claim requests. We carefully dispose of records and delete information when retention periods expire. 

Top of Page

**CUSTOMERS ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR PROTECTING INFORMATION AND SYSTEMS ON THEIR PREMISES**  
  
Some information about UPS customers and their packages is stored in shipping systems located on customer premises. Customers concerned about the security of their information in these systems should secure it by activating passwords and using physical access controls. When these systems (hardware or software) are provided by UPS, we provide tools to facilitate customer efforts to safeguard their information. Examples of these systems are UPS OnLineTM Professional, UPS OnLineTM Office, UPS OnLineTM Envoy and UPS OnLineTM WorldShip. 

Top of Page

**THE UPS WEB SITE AT WWW.UPS.COM**  
  
The following, indented paragraphs describe our commitment to the protection of personal information as it applies to the UPS Web site at www.ups.com. 

  |  **What Information We Collect And How We Will Use It**   
Users can visit most areas of the UPS Web site without revealing who they are or providing any information about themselves. However, some of our interactive services require that users identify themselves in order to enable the interactive function. We may ask users to provide some personal information in these situations.   
---|---  
   
  |   | **MY UPS.COM**   
Visitors to our site can, if they choose, participate in the interactive functions available at MY UPS.COM. Participants are required to complete a registration form. This form includes information such as name, address, phone number and e-mail address. We use the information from the registration form to enhance our services and better meet the needs and preferences of our customers. With approval, we may also send information to registered users about UPS products, services and system changes that we think may be of interest. We allow users to choose to discontinue (opt-out) from receiving information from UPS at any time by editing their Profile at [www.ups.com](http://www.ups.com/). 

MY UPS.COM also includes an Address Book that allows users to enter the names and addresses of the people to whom they frequently ship packages or letters. Use of the Address Book is optional. It is provided as a convenience so that users will not have to re-enter frequently used address information. The address information provided is stored in a secure manner on UPS systems. While it is stored in the Address Book, we will carefully protect the confidentiality of this information. It will not be used for any purpose other than the original intent (i.e. speeding up user shipping activities). 

**UPS Internet Shipping**   
Users of UPS Internet Shipping who choose to use credit cards for payment are required to provide information about themselves and their card. We use this information to establish credit for billing. 

**Web Surveys**   
From time to time, we include survey forms on our Web site asking users for contact and demographic information (such as postal code, age or size of company). We use the responses from the surveys to better understand our customer's needs and to create web sites that respond to their interests. Customers may opt-out of participating in follow-up surveys. UPS will not disclose survey response information to companies or individuals outside UPS with two exceptions: 

  1. Anonymized data, with all names, addresses and other personally identifiable information removed. 
  2. To vendors who are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are restricted from using the information for any purpose other than helping to provide services to UPS customers.

**Consent To Receive Promotional Material**   
MY UPS.COM allows users to opt out of receiving promotional material from us. The 'opt-out' feature applies to promotional material sent to our customers as a result of their participation in MY UPS.COM. Opting-out can be accomplished by editing the Member Profile in MY UPS.COM and removing the check-mark in the box labeled, "Please inform me about UPS service updates and UPS.com enhancements." 

**IP Addresses**   
The UPS Web site collects IP addresses for system administration, security, and statistical analysis purposes. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to a computer whenever it is connected to the Internet. We log these addresses and analyze them to understand where requests originate so that we can provide the most efficient service, enhance security, ensure appropriate usage and produce traffic volume statistics. 

**Cookies**   
Cookies are small text files that a Web site can send to a user's browser for storage on the hard drive. Cookies can make use of the Web easier by saving status and preferences about a web site. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies but users can change the setting to refuse cookies or to be alerted when cookies are being sent. 

We use cookies to keep track of customer status as a logged-on user of MY UPS.COM. Although acceptance of cookies will not interfere with the ability to interact with most of our web site, users will need to accept cookies in order to log-in and use MY UPS.COM. The cookies are renewed every time a user logs into MY UPS.COM. 

**Review, Modification, and Deletion of Personal Information**   
Participants in the MY UPS.COM program can review, modify, or delete the information previously provided at the registration site by editing their Profile information in MY UPS.COM. Review, add, and delete functions are also options within the Preferences and Address Book functions. Users should note that UPS will use reasonable efforts to delete user information when requested but that some residual information may remain because of backup files and deletion logs. 

**Expiration of Data**   
Personal information provided on the MY UPS.COM registration form will be deleted if the user does not access MY UPS.COM for 14 months.   
  
|  |   
  
Top of Page

**ASSENT**  
  
Your continued use of this site signifies your assent to the UPS Privacy Policy. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for changes. 

Top of Page

**CONTACTING UPS**  
  
If you have questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your experience on any of our UPS Web sites, you can contact: 

     Webmaster   
United Parcel Service   
55 Glenlake Pkwy   
Atlanta, GA 30328 

or at [webmaster@ups.com](mailto:webmaster@ups.com). 

Comments, suggestions or materials sent or transmitted to UPS shall be deemed to be non-confidential. UPS shall have no obligation of any kind with respect to such comments, suggestions or materials and shall be free to use and distribute them to others without limitation, including, but not limited to developing and marketing products incorporating them. 

Revised July 27, 1999 

Top of Page
|   
---  

| UPS at a Glance  
| The UPS Story  
| Year 2000 Readiness Disclosure  
| UPS Privacy Policy  
|   
  |   
|   |  Protection of Customer Information  
---|---  
  |  Shipment Information  
  |  Links To Other Sites  
  |  Security And Integrity Of Information  
  |  Retention Of Customer Information  
  |  Customers Are Responsible For Protecting Information And Systems On Their Premises  
  |  The UPS Web Site At WWW.UPS.COM  
  |  Assent  
  |  Contacting UPS  
|   
  
**PROTECTION OF CUSTOMER INFORMATION**  
  
We understand the importance of privacy to our customers and visitors to our Web site. For many years, our policy has been to treat what we learn about our customers as confidential. For example, we will not give or sell confidential or personal information about our customer to any third party not affiliated with their transaction, except as required by law or as necessary to provide UPS services to the customer. 

We collect and store information about every package we handle so that we can efficiently provide the package delivery services demanded by our customers. We use information about our customers, their packages, and their shipping activity to provide or enhance the services we make available to our customers, to enhance our ability to communicate with our customers about additional services they may find of value, to satisfy our legitimate business interests (including performing trend analysis and market studies), to set prices, establish credit, fulfill a Contract of Carriage or Service Agreement, accomplish the billing function, and to comply with government regulations. Although government regulations vary in the many countries in which we operate, they frequently include the reporting of information to transportation safety, customs, and other regulatory agencies. 

As we collect and use information about our customers, we may contract with vendors to assist us in processing that information. These vendors are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are restricted from using the information for any purpose other than helping to provide UPS services to our customers. 

Some of the information collected by UPS is personal data or data which relates to an identifiable person. Examples of personal data are names, addresses, e-mail addresses, credit card numbers and telephone numbers. We never sell information to third parties that could be used to specifically identify an individual customer or group of customers. Anonymized data, with all names, addresses and other personally identifiable information removed, is sometimes shared with third parties. Finally, we do provide personal data to government agencies as required by law or regulation. 

In addition to the uses of the information described in the paragraphs above, we collect telephone numbers and e-mail addresses in the event that we have to contact the shipper, or the shipment recipient, to resolve a question or provide shipment status information. 

Top of Page

**SHIPMENT INFORMATION**  
  
Information, including personal information (name, address and phone number), provided as part of a shipping transaction represents a record of that business transaction and cannot be altered after the transaction is complete except as provided in the UPS Terms and Conditions. The UPS Terms and Conditions are available at [www.ups.com](http://www.ups.com/) in the Service Guide section and at local UPS offices. 

Although we make reasonable efforts to limit access to our facilities and vehicles to authorized personnel, we are not responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of information that is printed and placed in plain view on a package or letter. 

Top of Page

**LINKS TO OTHER SITES**  
  
UPS provides links to external sites as a convenience to the user. The inclusion of any link does not imply UPS endorsement of the external site company, its web site, or the products and services it promotes and sells. UPS is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

Top of Page

**SECURITY AND INTEGRITY OF INFORMATION**  
  
We treat our data as assets that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ information security techniques to appropriately protect confidential information from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company. Access to customer information is limited to those employees who have a legitimate business need for that information. 

UPS Internet sites are currently located in the United States. UPS Internet sites, and their supporting systems, employ generally accepted information security techniques such as firewalls, access control procedures and cryptography to appropriately protect confidential information from unauthorized access. 

Top of Page

**RETENTION OF CUSTOMER INFORMATION**  
  
We retain information about customers as necessary for business purposes and as required by government regulation. For example, we retain information about packages, including names and addresses, so that we can provide proof of delivery information and to process claim requests. We carefully dispose of records and delete information when retention periods expire. 

Top of Page

**CUSTOMERS ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR PROTECTING INFORMATION AND SYSTEMS ON THEIR PREMISES**  
  
Some information about UPS customers and their packages is stored in shipping systems located on customer premises. Customers concerned about the security of their information in these systems should secure it by activating passwords and using physical access controls. When these systems (hardware or software) are provided by UPS, we provide tools to facilitate customer efforts to safeguard their information. Examples of these systems are UPS OnLineTM Professional, UPS OnLineTM Office, UPS OnLineTM Envoy and UPS OnLineTM WorldShip. 

Top of Page

**THE UPS WEB SITE AT WWW.UPS.COM**  
  
The following, indented paragraphs describe our commitment to the protection of personal information as it applies to the UPS Web site at www.ups.com. 

  |  **What Information We Collect And How We Will Use It**   
Users can visit most areas of the UPS Web site without revealing who they are or providing any information about themselves. However, some of our interactive services require that users identify themselves in order to enable the interactive function. We may ask users to provide some personal information in these situations.   
---|---  
   
  |   | **MY UPS.COM**   
Visitors to our site can, if they choose, participate in the interactive functions available at MY UPS.COM. Participants are required to complete a registration form. This form includes information such as name, address, phone number and e-mail address. We use the information from the registration form to enhance our services and better meet the needs and preferences of our customers. With approval, we may also send information to registered users about UPS products, services and system changes that we think may be of interest. We allow users to choose to discontinue (opt-out) from receiving information from UPS at any time by editing their Profile at [www.ups.com](http://www.ups.com/). 

MY UPS.COM also includes an Address Book that allows users to enter the names and addresses of the people to whom they frequently ship packages or letters. Use of the Address Book is optional. It is provided as a convenience so that users will not have to re-enter frequently used address information. The address information provided is stored in a secure manner on UPS systems. While it is stored in the Address Book, we will carefully protect the confidentiality of this information. It will not be used for any purpose other than the original intent (i.e. speeding up user shipping activities). 

**UPS Internet Shipping**   
Users of UPS Internet Shipping who choose to use credit cards for payment are required to provide information about themselves and their card. We use this information to establish credit for billing. 

**Web Surveys**   
From time to time, we include survey forms on our Web site asking users for contact and demographic information (such as postal code, age or size of company). We use the responses from the surveys to better understand our customer's needs and to create web sites that respond to their interests. Customers may opt-out of participating in follow-up surveys. UPS will not disclose survey response information to companies or individuals outside UPS with two exceptions: 

  1. Anonymized data, with all names, addresses and other personally identifiable information removed. 
  2. To vendors who are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are restricted from using the information for any purpose other than helping to provide services to UPS customers.

**Consent To Receive Promotional Material**   
MY UPS.COM allows users to opt out of receiving promotional material from us. The 'opt-out' feature applies to promotional material sent to our customers as a result of their participation in MY UPS.COM. Opting-out can be accomplished by editing the Member Profile in MY UPS.COM and removing the check-mark in the box labeled, "Please inform me about UPS service updates and UPS.com enhancements." 

**IP Addresses**   
The UPS Web site collects IP addresses for system administration, security, and statistical analysis purposes. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to a computer whenever it is connected to the Internet. We log these addresses and analyze them to understand where requests originate so that we can provide the most efficient service, enhance security, ensure appropriate usage and produce traffic volume statistics. 

**Cookies**   
Cookies are small text files that a Web site can send to a user's browser for storage on the hard drive. Cookies can make use of the Web easier by saving status and preferences about a web site. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies but users can change the setting to refuse cookies or to be alerted when cookies are being sent. 

We use cookies to keep track of customer status as a logged-on user of MY UPS.COM. Although acceptance of cookies will not interfere with the ability to interact with most of our web site, users will need to accept cookies in order to log-in and use MY UPS.COM. The cookies are renewed every time a user logs into MY UPS.COM. 

**Review, Modification, and Deletion of Personal Information**   
Participants in the MY UPS.COM program can review, modify, or delete the information previously provided at the registration site by editing their Profile information in MY UPS.COM. Review, add, and delete functions are also options within the Preferences and Address Book functions. Users should note that UPS will use reasonable efforts to delete user information when requested but that some residual information may remain because of backup files and deletion logs. 

**Expiration of Data**   
Personal information provided on the MY UPS.COM registration form will be deleted if the user does not access MY UPS.COM for 14 months.   
  
|  |   
  
Top of Page

**ASSENT**  
  
Your continued use of this site signifies your assent to the UPS Privacy Policy. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for changes. 

Top of Page

**CONTACTING UPS**  
  
If you have questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your experience on any of our UPS Web sites, you can contact: 

     Webmaster   
United Parcel Service   
55 Glenlake Pkwy   
Atlanta, GA 30328 

or at [webmaster@ups.com](mailto:webmaster@ups.com). 

Comments, suggestions or materials sent or transmitted to UPS shall be deemed to be non-confidential. UPS shall have no obligation of any kind with respect to such comments, suggestions or materials and shall be free to use and distribute them to others without limitation, including, but not limited to developing and marketing products incorporating them. 

Revised July 27, 1999 

Top of Page
